JACKSON ROBBINS

jackson@jacksonr.com (312) 429-7345

www.linkedin.com/in/jacksonrobbins606 https://jackrobbins1.github.io/

Chicago, IL 60622

WEB DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web development bootcamp graduate with more than 5 years of experience working directly with customers from industries that include technology, digital marketing, restaurant / hospitality, and beer. Proven track-record of providing excellent customer service and managing busy workload through strong organization and communication skills. Curious lifelong learner who enjoys studying complex systems and creative problem solving.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Business Operations
- Software Development
- Written and Verbal Communication
- Troubleshooting and Problem Solving
- Customer Service

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Working Knowledge: Ionic, Angular, Linux Ubuntu & CentOS, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, SCSS, Bootstrap, Material Design Lite, Git, Node.js, SalesForce, FreshDesk, RingCentral, Trello, Invision, Microsoft Suite, Google Suite Basic Knowledge: MySQL, Express, Docker, Gulp, Cordova, PHP, MongoDB, DigitalOcean, AWS, Netsuite, and Marketo

WORK EXPERIENCE

AMOpportunities — Chicago, IL

July 2018 — November 2018

Junior Web Developer

AMOpportunities develops an online platform that connects healthcare providers with medical students seeking clinical rotations. From AMO's founding in 2013, it has built a network of more than 250 healthcare partner sites and has helped thousands of students from more than 75 countries enroll in rotations.

- Worked as a contract employee to develop the front-end of AMO's web and mobile app using lonic.
- Built the user interface (UI) / look of the app by developing custom components, CSS, and TypeScript.
- Collaborated with AMO's various teams to gather input for the app and implement needed design changes.

MicroTrain Technologies — Chicago, IL

April 2018 — June 2018

Student

MicroTrain Technologies provides instructor-led training to individuals and corporations. The company was founded in 1999 and has provided innovative, hands-on training solutions to over 10,000 individual and corporate students.

- Intensive Full-Stack Web Development bootcamp lasting 10 weeks, with 40 hours of class per week.
- Acquired working proficiency with Ubuntu Linux and the MEAN stack (MongoDB / MySQL, Express, Angular, and Node.js).
- Learned hybrid mobile app development using Ionic.
- Learned the challenges of internet security and the methods developers use to protect their systems and users.

TouchBistro — Chicago, IL

July 2017 — October 2017

TouchBistro is a Toronto-based tech company that develops a restaurant point of sale (POS) system for the iPad that is named best-in-class software by Business News Daily, G2 Crowd Reviews and other industry publications.

- Handle Tier 1 customer support requests from inbound calls, emails, and tickets.
- Assist clients with account options, ongoing subscriptions / billing, and troubleshooting technical issues to maximize retention.
- Tracked metrics and customer feature requests via Salesforce to inform product roadmap and sales strategy.
- Developed guidebooks to document procedures and best practices to improve the quality and consistency of the support team's customer service.

Sleeve a Message — Chicago, IL

February 2017 — July 2017

Sales Representative at Chicago-based start up selling custom bar coasters & coffee sleeves

- Worked with CEO and VP of Sales to craft sales prospecting strategy of new customers and align sales team on best practices for ongoing CRM to maximize sales.
- Led projects to test new product positioning based on insights from experience in on-premise beer sales.
- Managed sales for greater Chicagoland area and ensured timely execution of all orders.

DialogTech — Chicago, IL

May 2016 — January 2017

Account Development Representative of call attribution technology

DialogTech is a Chicago-based tech company that develops inbound call tracking software for digital marketers. The platform offers a comprehensive suite of tools to measure phone calls from online advertising, route calls from the context of customers' needs, and analyze customer to call center conversations with AI.

- Worked with business development team to execute a prospecting strategy built from marketing mix data and webinar attendee lists.
- Discuss with prospective clients the data our software collects and how it can improve and integrate with their existing marketing systems
- Managed webinar campaign targeting financial institutions and generated reporting on overall response rate and engagement metrics to inform future client prospecting.
- Among top performing reps on team & held ranking for most appointments won within 3 months at company.

Louis Glunz Beers Inc. — Lincolnwood, IL

October 2012 — February 2016

Sales Representative: Northside Territory — Promoted February 2014

Louis Glunz Beer is a family-owned importer and distributor of beers located in Lincolnwood, IL. The company has operated for 130 years and transformed the Chicago-area marketplace by introducing the premium import and craft beer categories to beer drinkers.

- Managed sales for 140+ accounts in the Lakeview neighborhood of Chicago (on & off-premise).
- Responsible for selling more than 50,000 cases of beer per year.
- Sold 6% more cases of beer in second year vs. prior year.
- Utilized iDig to track sales performance and identify opportunities or issues in my book of accounts.

Merchandiser — Promoted May 2013

Ambassador of Beer — October 2012

Costa Rica's Craft Brewing Company — Cartago, Costa Rica

June 2011 — July 2011

Operations Assistant

- Created promotional media such as videos, brochures, and webpages.
- Trained as a brewmaster's assistant helping brewery operations and giving tours for customers.

EDUCATION

Macalester College — St. Paul, MN

August 2008 — May 2012

- Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA: 3.10)
- Senior thesis: "Beer Festivals and Visitors' Motivations for Attending"

Associated Colleges of the Midwest: Costa Rica Field Research Program

January 2011 — May 2011

Studied abroad and learned Spanish through living with host families and taking grammar courses.

Condu	cted independ	uction in Guana	acaste for 2 mo	nths.		